IL Cafe we have you
covered welcome to Il Cafe we're about
to discuss motor insurance today and you
know the thing is I've realized that you
think the question and we bring you the
answer even before you can say the
questions out in in words and that's how
quick we are I'm uh in a very self-
congratulatory mode as you can see today
but uh you get the drift over here we've
got a few of your questions answered on
today's show that is all about the
digital motor claim Journey so we've got
an expert who's going to be joining us
from the IC Lombard family today he's a
he's a leader with several years of
experience Rajiv mirani is joining us
he's vice president customer service
motor and strategy uh thank you s thank
you for having me here and would like to
give insight about the M claims Journey
on the digital site which is a new age
uh a landscape of technology using
technology and uh making customer life
easier and I thought you know we should
start with an icebreaker question
because just this morning I was thinking
about the very first car that I ever
owned with my own money and that was a I
think esteem one of those old you know
maroon color esteem is what I had but
I'm sure you know each one of us has a
special memory associated with vehicles
that we have owned what's yours Raji
before we get into the business end of
the conversation all right so same here
you know that time or those days uh we
were having all maruti so I even started
my journey with uh 800 Mar which used to
be a public car or the famous car and uh
I still remember that was one of the
best TRS on those days and uh we learned
you know how to drive on this particular
car it was a you know family car for
those days you know you are lucky Rajiv
if you learned on one I learned in a
Fiat so for us you know any Mar of the
road was like wow what a what a car so I
completely hear you nice family car a
nice way to you know sort of remember
those days on a show like this one as
well and then of course move into the
business end of questions we've heard so
much you know uh with respect to the
sector evolving and with respect
specifically to motor claims and would
be good to understand what has changed
with respect to customer expectations
and the industry landscape uh in the
last say few years or so according to
you Rajiv so on the motor CLE side
basically you know the objective of the
insurance uh companies is to make
customers life easier by you know using
technology and uh when we say technology
uh there are a lot of initiatives being
a industry leader we have taken a lot of
initiatives and you know we have
launched uh certain industry first
initiatives like uh you know Cloud
calling eclaims paperless Journey instas
SP then we have uh cashless garages
Network and uh you know so many so we we
keep on you know adding uh features for
you know making the life easier and you
know provide a better experience to the
customers you mentioned quite a few of
these interventions Rajiv would be good
for our customers our viewers to
understand what each of these is really
all about and what paino or challenge or
need gap does it address so if you could
take one by one and explain a little bit
more to us so s basically for customer
it's a pain you know is already going
through a pain of you know accident
which is unfortunate event for him and
we would not like our customer to face
that but in case the need arises we are
there to support uh from starting from
ination to uh the payment Journey so end
to end Journey we want to support the
customer we want to stand with the
customers uh and ensure that you know he
doesn't face any challenges so if we
talk about the initiatives uh you know
uh recently we have launched uh Cloud
calling features so basically this
feature is all about you know we are
empowering customers to connect with our
claims manager uh through one single
point uh contact number and the customer
can you know get the query addressed
from Real Time bus as when required okay
so that uh all the customer queries are
not remain unanswered that is the
objective and secondly the benefit is
all these calls are recorded uh so you
know we get uh we get a chance to
analyze those calls and train the team
on the you know soft skill as well as uh
the query resolutions okay so we keep on
you know uh improving our skill sets and
our uh Communications that's the
objective so this uh you know till date
if we talk about we were able to you
know solve the queries of customers uh
almost 95% plus and we were able to
connect uh more than 10 lakh customers
as on today right and uh see generally
what happens is in traditional ways uh
nobody you know wants to Face customer
or nobody uh you know people uh uh skips
to connect to customer and give a better
experience or you know comfort you know
sitting at their homes so customer need
not to visit garages because and they
feel that you know they are not aware of
the process so customer if you guide
properly they will be you know taken
care and there'll be a smooth journey
and the seamless experience what we are
looking at so that's all about
Cloud calling if we talk about there's a
insta aspect where you know customer can
connect with us on Real Time Business uh
sitting at their home through online uh
application where we are able to you
know get vehicle surveyed with an
approval right on the you know call so
that customer need not to worry about
you know when the survey will happen how
survey will happen and you know how long
it will take to provide an approach
because traditionally it was taking a
lot of time
so involvement of garages Etc which is
not the case here we we are there to you
know attend the customer calls and uh
you know survey on real time bis so how
that is what we are solving through
instas speec then we have eclaim uh so
earlier you know traditionally all the
industry you know takes lot of paperwork
so customer feel Inon you know
submitting a lot of papers uh and you
know signing papers Etc so here we are
saying you just need not to submit any
paper physical papers so we provide
online Link where customer can fill the
you know minimum bare minimum details
and uh that's it you can also upload the
document online so need not to visit any
garage need not to visit any offices you
do not call customer at our branches so
that uh you know it's easy for customer
to file a claim right it's not uh
difficult for him to make a claim uh and
eclaim is also available with ckyc
online right so otherwise now is Cy kyc
is another you know you have to submit
extra paper for address proof ID proof
Etc which is not the case here so we do
this with e-claim only and then we have
Breakin application which is you know AI
enabled which helps customer to renew
the policy uh setting at their homes on
the real di So within you know 78
minutes the uh you know approvals are
given so you can issue the policy uh on
immediate basis there is no need to wait
no need to you know wait for surveyor to
inspect the vehicle at home next day and
third day and you know takes time so
that's all about uh breaking app
WhatsApp Journey so now customers are
very happy to you know have the updates
on realtime studies because there are
lot of stages in the claims like you
know intimation surveyor is appointed
surveyor inspects the vehicle and then
you know approvals are given then the
repairs uh starts and the repair
completion then delivery order and you
know the liability one so everything is
on Real Time basis on daily basis we
keep on updating our status on the
customer mobile so that he's able to you
know view the real time status of claim
so that he need not to call anyone he
need not to you know worry about what is
happening on my car we are even showing
them you know very real status also so
you can have a complete view about the
claim status on daily so that's the
objective and then we have you know chat
BS voice BS where customer can even uh
you know raise the query or the you know
address their queries even if he don't
want to talk that is also physic so s
basically you know uh to make the life
easy and you know seamless to provide
better experience to customers we have
you know initiatives we already taken
this initiatives like uh instas speec
Cloud calling WhatsApp Journey then
eclaim paperless uh you know Journeys
and uh inbu ckyc Breakin application so
we have done lot of uh usage of
Technology uh to make uh you know
process simple and uh easy there's one
more phrase right you know that sort of
captured my imagination because we've
heard cashless in the context of Health
Right medical claims cashless
hospitalization but cashless garage is a
new new phrase that I'm hearing and I'm
thinking
uh what amazing use cases there could be
for something like this we all recently
you know a few months ago we read about
uh the floods in chenai and we used to
wonder at that time you always think
about the pain that the person is going
through having lost all these luxury
cars just because of rain Mother Nature
um tell us a little bit in the context
of uh you know how this helps consumers
so thank you SE for bringing you know uh
this castless discussion so castless is
a FAS for you know customer to Avail
that benefit so that customer need not
to Bear the entire cost of claim and you
know pay from pocket and then go through
the you know reimbursement process which
is ideally a leny to avoid that you know
inconvenience to our customers what we
have made is we have uh you know set up
the arrangement of the garage across all
locations across all em manufacturers so
that as and when the claim arises we
arrange the cast
facility at that particular garage and
we ensure that customer just pay the you
know minimum amount what he's supposed
to pay and uh rest enre you know the
bill or the liability is paid to garage
directly without any hurdles and
customer need not to wait for you know
reimbursement of claim uh which
generally takes you know 15 to 20 days
time and we cut down this process in
short u Gess is a big benefit for the
holders and uh we would like to you know
extend all all the support to our
customers to you know arrange this
facility uh and use this facility to
make their life uh comfortable and uh
hle free on the next Point C uh Cyclone
Mong uh which happened recently in
Chennai uh that you know lot of
customers uh Vehicles got affected even
the you know and we we understood the
you know impact of this uh particular
tragedy uh and what we did is uh we
arranged Manpower from different
locations and you know uh we arrang a
task force in Chennai to uh you know
first to address the or to you know
provide empathy to customers by you know
standing with them and supporting them
by you know arranging Towing Vans and
even the you know appointment with the
garages uh we did certain you know camps
in the society so that customers are you
know uh uh given some reliefs in terms
of you know they we are there with them
to support the claims or you know
whatever help we we were able to extend
so we we expanded the teams we sent the
experts across the Ops and uh we started
you know arranging uh pickups and uh
appointment Etc with the garage and then
we started assessing the laws and today
uh I'm very happy that you know within a
month's time we were able to to deliver
or you know settle off 80 more than 80%
of claims within a short notice where
you know people were uh if you look at
the industry this numbers would not be
that big but yes we were focused we we
are having enough teams uh to with the
customers we were able to deliver this
numbers in a very short spine of time
right and the customer were happy we get
lot of appreciation from customers
saying you know we were lucky to have
insurance with you is the reason we are
today you know out of this uh trauma
that's a very powerful story about how
you know not just technology but teams
can come together to address you know
people's concerns at a time when
everything seems to be up in the air you
don't know where to go what to do you're
Frozen because this is not something
that you anticipate and it happens to
you so um that that's a lovely lovely
story that you shared with us with
respect to the power of putting together
processes that make a customer's life so
easy even in challenging times like uh
the example that you gave us in summary
you know Rajiv is there anything that
you would like to leave our viewers with
when they think about motor claim
process any last words from uh you as
someone who heads that particular area
for us so uh so s basically see of
course digital uh process digital
digitalization of claims process is uh
uh equally important but you know we
also know that you know physical touch
is equally important so we always you
know touch B the customer once in a uh
you know the claim process so that we do
not miss uh you know the opportunity to
get feedback from the customers and uh
we also wanted to understand the pulse
of the you know customer so that we are
constantly you know building up the
process building up the uh technology
and uh you know deliver the promises
what we have made while you know
purchasing the policy and by you know
doing all this efforts are basically to
ensure that we are transparent we are
fair we are you know responsible and we
we you know care for customer is the you
know uh theme or the objective of this
uh claim process right or to make you
know life easier during the entire
Journey end to end Journey we want to be
there with the customers and we assure
that you know our customers uh in
whatever situation they are we are there
for them and we will always be uh you
know willing to extend our best possible
efforts and support during the
challenging times before I wrap up the
conversation remember right in the
beginning we spoke about the first ever
car and we uh refreshed some of our old
memories I thought you know maybe some
more memories to sign off the
conversation because a car is integral
it's a part of our life right it takes
us to places it's it's more it's
symbolic of Continuum in in many ways
and music is part of that Journey so I I
was wondering you know do you also have
like a playlist because when I get into
the car I have a particular playlist
that I like to listen to it's got a mix
it's got some old kishor Kumar songs it
has some arit Singh songs it has some
English old 80s music as well what's
your go-to song or set of songs when you
are
driving I'm fan of you know SP balas
'90s you know there there were a lot of
famous songs he song for us
and that is memorable I think you and I
have something in common over here
because one of my favorite set of songs
to listen to are from many I don't know
why but on long drives I really like to
listen all of the
songs but and ashiki that's not STV but
ashiki songs are out of the world uh so
the
19 yeah right you agree right sjan
asiki correct corre right man he did
great music in the 90s anyway that's our
drive time playlist I hope our listeners
have taken away some things to add to
their own playlists as they drive out
and please do remember to drive safe
safe and belt up not just in the front
seats but also in the back seats if you
have kids make sure they're always
belted up and on that note uh let us
wrap up the show thank you so much Raji
for joining us on I Cafe today thank you
s for having us here thank you so much